# Joseph N. Beach Software Engineer / Full Stack Developer

Oconomowoc, WI 53066 · 618-975-5760 <u>jnbeach48@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Website</u>

#### **Summary of Qualifications**

Microsoft Software & Systems Academy graduate with proficiency in C# and .NET application development. Veteran Nuclear Submarine Officer with eight years of experience in Engineering and Program Management, Quality Assurance, and Regulatory Compliance. Specific skills and experience include:

- C#, VBA, and .NET Applications
- HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- SQL, Databases, and Data Analysis
- Object Oriented Program Design

- Azure and Online/Cloud Services
- Engineering Leadership / Management
- Quality Assurance / Regulatory Compliance
- Human Resources and Career Management

#### **Work Experience**

#### Regulatory Affairs Leader, May 2019 - Sep 2021

GE Healthcare, Magnetic Resonance Imaging - Waukesha, WI

- Automated data entry into GE's regulatory database information systems by developing scripts using Visual Basic, Excel, and Selenium Web driver. Improved entry times by 80%.
- Streamlined global product registration processes by developing templates and standardizing data acquisition leading to 20% improvement in approval times. Spearheaded company documentation updates for new regulatory requirements.

#### Placement Officer, Jan 2017 - Apr 2019

Navy Personnel Command (PERS-42) - Millington, TN

- Maximized operational readiness through worldwide human resource management of more than 320,000 Navy personnel. Managed the distribution and career progression of 5,200 nuclear trained naval officers. Executed an annual budget totaling \$30 million.
- Identified inefficiencies in data retrieval and developed automated retrieval and analysis methods using Excel, Cobalt, and Visual Basic.

### Nuclear Submarine Officer, Jan 2014 - Jan 2017

USS Connecticut (SSN-22) - Bremerton, WA

- Senior level supervisor of 80 mechanics and electricians involved in the repair and operation of a reactor powering a \$3 billion submarine.
- Ranked #1 of 12 officers during periodic peer evaluations.
- Organized and executed complex technical training and drills.
   Accomplished 100% passing rates on self-administered exams.
- Hand chosen to independently manage the submarine's Quality
  Assurance program. Managed periodic audits and surveillances to
  critique work processes and identify administrative discrepancies,
  resulting in continuous program improvement.
- Processed hundreds of maintenance documents, ensuring rigid adherence to procedures and technical specifications, resulting in flawless undocking and return to operation of the USS Connecticut.
- Watch team supervisor, with an overall responsibility for the safety and security of a crew of 130.

#### **Education**

#### **United States Naval Academy**

B.S. in Physics GPA: 3.88, 2007 - 2011 (#45 out of 1025)

#### **Naval Postgraduate School**

M.S. in Applied Physics GPA: 3.75, 2011 - 2012

#### **Training**

## Microsoft Software and Systems Academy

Program graduate
C# Programming, Data
Integration, and Azure.

#### Self-Learning

MTA 98-361 Certified Web Development Raspberry Pi / Bash Scripts Python / Unity

## Naval Nuclear Power Training

Certified Nuclear Engineer Coursework in physics, chemistry, engineering, and nuclear reactor design and operations.

#### **Hobbies**

Video Games Computer Building Music Production Competitive Fencing